<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>talks on Sachita Nishal</title>
    <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/tags/talks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in talks on Sachita Nishal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nishalsach.github.io/tags/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A prototype newsgathering tool for science journalists</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2024-11-01-cplusj-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2024-11-01-cplusj-blog/</guid>
      <description>This past month, I presented our recent work on using LLMs to aid science journalists in reading complex scientific papers. Here&amp;rsquo;s the link to my blog post about it, published on the Generative AI in the Newsroom blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk &#43; Responses: Blueprints for Evaluating AI in Journalism</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2024-05-02-ai-evals-aspen-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2024-05-02-ai-evals-aspen-talk/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I delivered a short talk at Aspen Digital&amp;rsquo;s event called AI &amp;amp; News: Charting the Course. It was hosted at the Ford Foundation Center for Social Justice in NYC, which is a really pretty venue. They have so many trees inside! And also apprently: birds1! Here&amp;rsquo;s the slide deck for this talk, made under a certain degree of sleep deprivation-based duress and fever brain.
Pretty trees! This was a really fun time for me for a bunch of reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk &#43; Responses: Gender Biases in LLM Narratives</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2024-04-02-story-discovery-at-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2024-04-02-story-discovery-at-scale/</guid>
      <description>Last week I delivered a short talk at Big Local News&amp;rsquo; conference Story Discovery at Scale 2024. It was great to be back this year &amp;ndash; 2023 was my first time attending this event, and meeting the groups around Big Local News! I felt like I was going back to a community of people that I now know and understand a little better, and it was nice to have some familiar faces to say hello to and catch up with.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
