<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sachita Nishal</title>
    <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sachita Nishal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nishalsach.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Turn off the GPT Scraper? In this [Attention] Economy?</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2023-10-02-attention-gpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2023-10-02-attention-gpt/</guid>
      <description>After all the hullabaloo around generative models like ChatGPT, BARD, and others helping their parent companies profit off the intellectual property produced by news outlets (and artists and writers but they are not really in the purview of this post), there seem to be some inklings of legislative action, at least in the U.S. For one, representatives of news outlets regional and local, big and small, recently met with lawmakers to discuss copyright protections for their work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading and Writing Files in Python: Modifiers</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2023-05-23-reading-writing-modifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2023-05-23-reading-writing-modifiers/</guid>
      <description>Different modes of reading and writing to files, and what they do:
r: Only read. This is the default if no mode argument is given.
w: Only write. An existing file with the same name will be over-written.
a: Append data to the end of the file. Still writing.
r+: Both reading and writing and can be done. I never use this.
From the Python Docs:
Normally, files are opened in text mode, that means, you read and write strings from and to the file, which are encoded in a specific encoding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BeautifulSoup4Dummies</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2023-05-19-bs4dummies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2023-05-19-bs4dummies/</guid>
      <description>Note: All links are from BS v4.12.0 documentation and reference, but the gist should probably hold for a while.
BeautifulSoup4 + Python is a formidable combo for web-scraping when the territory I&amp;rsquo;m scraping in is uncertain, webpages are static, and I need to spin up something quick and dirty so I can hunt around through the HTML to specifically extract what I need.
Another thing is: when pulling web data with BS4, sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s really handy to keep separate files of the subset/tags/text in a page that are of interest, but then also save original HTML files just to have them on hand in case extraction does not go according to plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Archival Publications From Crowd Ratings to Predictive Models of Newsworthiness to Support Science Journalism
Sachita Nishal and Nick Diakopoulos
Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction (CSCW) 2022.
PDF ACM DL Voting with the Stars: Analyzing Partisan Engagement between Celebrities and Politicians in India
Ramaravind Kommiya Mothilal, Dibyendu Mishra, Sachita Nishal, Faisal M. Lalani, Joyojeet Pal
Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction (CSCW) 2022.
PDF ACM DL Devotees on an Astroturf: Media, Politics, and Outrage in the Suicide of a Popular Film Star</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Years into the PhD: Thoughts and Half-thoughts</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2022-10-27-evaluating-my-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2022-10-27-evaluating-my-phd/</guid>
      <description>One thing I did not (really, truly, practically) take into consideration when I started doing the PhD was how difficult it would be. I learnt soon enough, of course. But you know that joke &amp;ndash; that the best time to be in a PhD program is the summer before it begins, when you impress everyone by telling them you&amp;rsquo;re going to get a PhD without having to actually do anything for it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Short Primer on Mutual Information</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2022-04-25-short-primer_mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2022-04-25-short-primer_mi/</guid>
      <description>Definitions Conceptual Definition: MI is the reduction in uncertainty when predicting one variable (&amp;ldquo;outcome&amp;rdquo;) in a system, if we know the value of another variable in the system. It will always be &amp;gt;=0, and higher values mean higher dependency between the two variables Formula (for discrete processes/variables X1 and X2): As must be apparent, for two independent variables, MI = 0. Eg. Two coins are tossed; the results of one coin do not help us measure the results of the other in any way Another way to look at this (and I still have some trouble wrapping my head around this) is that MI is the KL Divergence in going from the joint distribution P(X1, X2) to the product of the marginal distributions P(X1).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Inside Scikit-Learn Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2021-08-17-debugging-sklearn-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 18:01:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2021-08-17-debugging-sklearn-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>Click the given link to skip to the code and spare yourself my tortuous introduction: code for sklearn Pipeline debugging Transformer. Don&amp;rsquo;t click the link if you&amp;rsquo;re debugging at 2pm on a slow Thursday and want something, anything, to distract you from staring at VSCode and its quickly blurring lines of code. I can help you pretend you&amp;rsquo;re working as you scan the next few paragraphs of my inner monologue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thesis Experience at Northwestern University</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2020-06-29-thesis_northwestern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 13:39:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2020-06-29-thesis_northwestern/</guid>
      <description>In 2019, I completed my undergrad thesis at Northwestern University, where I worked in Dr. Luis Amaral&amp;rsquo;s lab to model complex networks of tropes in American films starting from the 1890s.
I wrote a brief account of how I applied for my thesis, as well as my takeaways from this momentous experience, and it was published on BITS Goa&amp;rsquo;s blog for undergrad research experiences. Here&amp;rsquo;s a link to the post: Sachita Nishal’s Thesis at Northwestern University!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posters for Plays</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/cool_stuff/play_posters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 12:37:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/cool_stuff/play_posters/</guid>
      <description>Hi, here&amp;rsquo;s some posters from my plays that I&amp;rsquo;ve adored and cherished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Hacks</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2020-06-12-hugo-hacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 18:01:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2020-06-12-hugo-hacks/</guid>
      <description>Hi.
Welcome.
You can choose to skip right to the hacks with this handy index:
Filepaths in Hugo Footnotes in Markdown HTML Tags for Images in Markdown Syntax Highlighting for Code in Markdown Or, you can bear witness to an overly detailed and meandering tale about my journey navigating the horrific ills of modern technology, below.
So, I am proud to announce that as of today, June 12 2020, I have transitioned out of Jekyll, and am the owner of a shiny new blog built with Hugo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even More About Me</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/cool_stuff/2020-06-16-cool-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 14:45:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/cool_stuff/2020-06-16-cool-stuff/</guid>
      <description>Books and Stuff Oct 2022: I&amp;rsquo;m currently reading James Gleick&amp;rsquo;s book, The Information, which provides a very detailed history of humanity&amp;rsquo;s relationship with information - oral, written, digital, all kinds! I&amp;rsquo;m really enjoying it because it weaves a wide-ranging set of ideas, people, and locations together to tell the story of how we&amp;rsquo;ve understood, catalogued, and communicated our ideas over the ages, and how the media that we use for these purposes has changed how we think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Goan summer sunsets can be spectacular! Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Sachita, and I am a 3rd-year PhD student at Northwestern University in Technology and Social Behaviour, a joint PhD program spanning Communication Studies 💬 and Computer Science 🖥️.
I work right at the intersection of human-computer interaction and journalism, and design information retrieval/recommender systems that help science and tech journalists explore newsworthy scientific research, and further investigate it for their reporting. We just published some new work about the human-centered design, and preliminary evaluation of such a recommender system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons From a Massive(ly-Annoying) Scraping Project in Python</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2019-09-16-lessons-from-a-massively-annoying-scraping-project-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2019-09-16-lessons-from-a-massively-annoying-scraping-project-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Hello!
I&amp;rsquo;m honestly quite unsure of what SEO miracle led you here, given the enthusiastically descriptive, but less than optimal title for this post. I&amp;rsquo;m further unsure of why you actually clicked this link when it showed up. But does that make me any less grateful that you&amp;rsquo;re here? Certainly not!
I wrote this post to document my experiences while scraping a massive crowdsourced website called TVTropes. During this venture, I spent many an afternoon quite desperately Googling &amp;ldquo;ugh web-scraping is so annoying save me python&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
