<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sachita Nishal</title>
    <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sachita Nishal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 13:39:12 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nishalsach.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thesis Experience at Northwestern University</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2020-06-29-thesis_northwestern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 13:39:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2020-06-29-thesis_northwestern/</guid>
      <description>In 2019, I completed my undergrad thesis at Northwestern University, where I worked in Dr. Luis Amaral&amp;rsquo;s lab to model complex networks of tropes in American films starting from the 1890s.
I wrote a brief account of how I applied for my thesis, as well as my takeaways from this momentous experience, and it was published on BITS Goa&amp;rsquo;s blog for undergrad research experiences. Here&amp;rsquo;s a link to the post: Sachita Nishal’s Thesis at Northwestern University!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posters for Plays</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/cool_stuff/play_posters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 12:37:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/cool_stuff/play_posters/</guid>
      <description>Hi, here&amp;rsquo;s some posters from my plays that I&amp;rsquo;ve adored and cherished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staples</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/cool_stuff/poems/staples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 02:59:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/cool_stuff/poems/staples/</guid>
      <description>there’s always certain staples in my mind,
not quite glued in,
but sort of tackily clipped on somewhere in the gaps.
they come in flashes and in those mini chunks of moments -
on the bus, walking through a doorway,
squeezing soap out on my palms,
or while zipping up a really full suitcase.
like that really colourful human evolution network diagram thingy
i saw in a science museum once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentle</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/cool_stuff/poems/gentle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 02:42:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/cool_stuff/poems/gentle/</guid>
      <description>hush, quiet now,
the dawn isn’t here yet.
it won’t be here for another hour or two.
or maybe you will snap your fingers (softly, surely!),
and it will unveil itself,
chirp by chirp,
until the sky’s blue sneaks in,
from between the crevices of your curtains.
you will have spent the night,
rubbing the soles of your feet underneath the table,
wishing they were gentler.
pausing to press down on</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Hacks</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2020-06-12-hugo-hacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 18:01:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2020-06-12-hugo-hacks/</guid>
      <description>Hi.
Welcome.
You can choose to skip right to the hacks with this handy index:
 Filepaths in Hugo Footnotes in Markdown HTML Tags for Images in Markdown Syntax Highlighting for Code in Markdown  Or, you can bear witness to an overly detailed and meandering tale about my journey navigating the horrific ills of modern technology, below.
So, I am proud to announce that as of today, June 12 2020, I have transitioned out of Jekyll, and am the owner of a shiny new blog built with Hugo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Stuff</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/cool_stuff/2020-06-16-cool-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 14:45:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/cool_stuff/2020-06-16-cool-stuff/</guid>
      <description>.myDiv { /* border: 5px outset red;*/ height: 630px; text-align: center; margin:10; }  Books and Stuff My Reading List has, on average, 47 books on it at any given point of time. However, my most ambitious project by far has been to finally complete the Discworld books! Ever since I read Guards! Guards! earlier this year, I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to get my hands on the entire series. So here I am, stuck at home in the Age of COVID, currently reading: Sourcery (7/41)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>-- Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Sachita Nishal, and I study Computer Science at BITS Pilani in Goa. Welcome to my homepage! In Fall 2020, I will be joining Northwestern University as a PhD student in Technology and Social Behaviour, an interdisciplinary program spanning Communication Studies and Computer Science. Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m interning with Dr. Joyojeet Pal in the Technology for Emerging Markets group at Microsoft Research, India.
I completed my undergraduate thesis under Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons From a Massive(ly-Annoying) Scraping Project in Python</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2019-09-16-lessons-from-a-massively-annoying-scraping-project-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2019-09-16-lessons-from-a-massively-annoying-scraping-project-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Hello!
I&amp;rsquo;m honestly quite unsure of what SEO miracle led you here, given the enthusiastically descriptive, but less than optimal title for this post. I&amp;rsquo;m further unsure of why you actually clicked this link when it showed up. But does that make me any less grateful that you&amp;rsquo;re here? Certainly not!
I wrote this post to document my experiences while scraping a massive crowdsourced website called TVTropes. During this venture, I spent many an afternoon quite desperately Googling &amp;ldquo;ugh web-scraping is so annoying save me python&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>