<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>research on Sachita Nishal</title>
    <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in research on Sachita Nishal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 18:01:26 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nishalsach.github.io/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Inside Scikit-Learn Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2021-08-17-debugging-sklearn-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 18:01:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2021-08-17-debugging-sklearn-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>Click the given link to skip to the code and spare yourself my tortuous introduction: code for sklearn Pipeline debugging Transformer. Don&amp;rsquo;t click the link if you&amp;rsquo;re debugging at 2pm on a slow Thursday and want something, anything, to distract you from staring at VSCode and its quickly blurring lines of code. I can help you pretend you&amp;rsquo;re working as you scan the next few paragraphs of my inner monologue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thesis Experience at Northwestern University</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2020-06-29-thesis_northwestern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 13:39:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2020-06-29-thesis_northwestern/</guid>
      <description>In 2019, I completed my undergrad thesis at Northwestern University, where I worked in Dr. Luis Amaral&amp;rsquo;s lab to model complex networks of tropes in American films starting from the 1890s.
I wrote a brief account of how I applied for my thesis, as well as my takeaways from this momentous experience, and it was published on BITS Goa&amp;rsquo;s blog for undergrad research experiences. Here&amp;rsquo;s a link to the post: Sachita Nishal’s Thesis at Northwestern University!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons From a Massive(ly-Annoying) Scraping Project in Python</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2019-09-16-lessons-from-a-massively-annoying-scraping-project-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2019-09-16-lessons-from-a-massively-annoying-scraping-project-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Hello!
I&amp;rsquo;m honestly quite unsure of what SEO miracle led you here, given the enthusiastically descriptive, but less than optimal title for this post. I&amp;rsquo;m further unsure of why you actually clicked this link when it showed up. But does that make me any less grateful that you&amp;rsquo;re here? Certainly not!
I wrote this post to document my experiences while scraping a massive crowdsourced website called TVTropes. During this venture, I spent many an afternoon quite desperately Googling &amp;ldquo;ugh web-scraping is so annoying save me python&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>