<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>human-computer interaction on Sachita Nishal</title>
    <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/tags/human-computer-interaction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in human-computer interaction on Sachita Nishal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nishalsach.github.io/tags/human-computer-interaction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>19 Mar 2024: Where the Month Went</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/readings/2024-03-15-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/readings/2024-03-15-reading/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I wrote these posts, and I think it&amp;rsquo;s not for lack of reading, but for lack of engaging with newer papers. I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot more reading and writing for my prospectus, which majorly involves re-treading my own work as well as stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve already read and cited.
That being said, I&amp;rsquo;ve read a few books this year! Focusing on books has been an interesting change of pace than reading tons of one-off essays or papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sorting Things Out, by Geoffrey Bowker and Susan Star (2000)</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/readings/2024-03-14-sorting-things-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/readings/2024-03-14-sorting-things-out/</guid>
      <description>I read this over the Fall and Winter quarters with our HCI+Design Book Club at Northwestern. It&amp;rsquo;s a landmark work in HCI and had been on my bucket list for a long time, so I was glad to finally get to it, and wrest with some of its more complex and thought-provoking themes in our little reading group. We read a chapter a week and the result of this was that I genuinely really enjoyed reading it and digging into its meaty bits1!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Years into the PhD: Thoughts and Half-thoughts</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2022-10-27-evaluating-my-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2022-10-27-evaluating-my-phd/</guid>
      <description>One thing I did not (really, truly, practically) take into consideration when I started doing the PhD was how difficult it would be. I learnt soon enough, of course. But you know that joke &amp;ndash; that the best time to be in a PhD program is the summer before it begins, when you impress everyone by telling them you&amp;rsquo;re going to get a PhD without having to actually do anything for it?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
