<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>news-industry on Sachita Nishal</title>
    <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/tags/news-industry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in news-industry on Sachita Nishal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nishalsach.github.io/tags/news-industry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Talk &#43; Responses: Blueprints for Evaluating AI in Journalism</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2024-05-02-ai-evals-aspen-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/2024-05-02-ai-evals-aspen-talk/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I delivered a short talk at Aspen Digital&amp;rsquo;s event called AI &amp;amp; News: Charting the Course. It was hosted at the Ford Foundation Center for Social Justice in NYC, which is a really pretty venue. They have so many trees inside! And also apprently: birds1! Here&amp;rsquo;s the slide deck for this talk, made under a certain degree of sleep deprivation-based duress and fever brain.
Pretty trees! This was a really fun time for me for a bunch of reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Feb 2024: Where the Week Went</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/readings/2024-02-02-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/readings/2024-02-02-reading/</guid>
      <description>Cool readings and excerpts from this week:
The Business of the News Lots of news in January about media downsizing and layoffs. The news industry in the U.S. looks like it is in a precarious position, but I feel like it&amp;rsquo;s also been this way for a while now. In the meanwhile, Joshua Benton of Nieman Lab reminds us that while it can feel like the industry is in freefall, sometimes outlets can simply collapse because they were ill-conceived, ego-driven projects that were terribly run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>26 Jan 2024: Where the Week Went</title>
      <link>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/readings/2024-01-26-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nishalsach.github.io/posts/readings/2024-01-26-reading/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m trying out something new this year, where I maintain a log of cool things I read (or watch, or listen to) around my work or academic interests. I think logging and describing these things can be good for my sense-making process in the long term, or generally help me feel sane when I look at the calendar on a Friday and exclaim &amp;ldquo;Where did the week go? 🫠&amp;rdquo;. Now, I will know, where the week went.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
